# Philipp Schröppel

PHD STUDENT IN COMPUTER VISION AT THE UNIVERSITY OF FREIRING

Freiburg i. Br., Germany

■ schroepp@cs.uni-freiburg.de | ★ https://pschroeppel.github.io



### Personal Information \_\_\_\_\_

Name Philipp Schröppel

Address 79106 Freiburg i. Br., Germany
Mail schroepp@cs.uni-freiburg.de

**Birthyear** 1992 **Nationality** German

#### Research\_

My broad research area is **3D reconstruction in terms of 3D geometry, ego-motion and object motion**. A particular focus is robust application on arbitrary real-world data. To this end, I am interested in:

- multi-view depth estimation,
- single-view depth estimation,
- optical flow estimation,

- scene flow estimation,
- depth-from-video,
- implicit 3D scene representations (neural fields).

Recently, I worked on **3D generation using diffusion models**. Currently, I am most interested in fundamental research on diffusion models, and in using scene priors learnt by diffusion models for 3D reconstruction.

Silvio Galasso\* Philipp Schröppel\* Hesan Dries Thomas Broy Diffusion for Out-of-Distribution Detection on

## **Publications**

#### CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS (\* denotes equal contribution)

ECCV 2024	Road Scenes and Beyond. European Conference on Computer Vision , 2024.
CVPR 2024	<b>Philipp Schröppel</b> , Christopher Wewer, Jan Eric Lenssen, Eddy Ilg, Thomas Brox. <i>Neural Point Cloud Diffusion for Disentangled 3D Shape and Appearance Generation</i> . Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2024.
3DV 2022	<b>Philipp Schröppel</b> , Jan Bechtold, Artemij Amiranashvili, Thomas Brox. <i>A Benchmark and a Baseline for</i>

Robust Multi-view Depth Estimation. International Conference on 3D Vision, 2022.

GCPR 2022 Leonhard Sommer, **Philipp Schröppel**, Thomas Brox. *SF2SE3: Clustering Scene Flow into SE(3)-Motions via Proposal and Selection*. German Conference on Patter Recognition, 2022.

#### WORKSHOP PAPERS (\* denotes equal contribution)

CVPR 2021 Julia Guerrero-Viu\*, Sergio Izquierdo\*, **Philipp Schröppel**, Thomas Brox. *Semi-Supervised Disparity Estimation with Deep Feature Reconstruction*. Women in Computer Vision Workshop, 2021.

# Teaching & Mentoring \_\_\_\_\_

2020	Master Thesis: Lal Jose. Monocular Camera Tracking for Driving Scenarios.
2020 - 2021	Master Project: Saurav Shanu. Stixel Prediction with an End-to-end deep Network.
2020 - 2021	Master Project: Sergio Izquierdo Barranco. Deep Feature Reconstruction for Disparity Estimation with DispNet.
2020 - 2021	Master Project: Julia Guerrero-Viu. Semi-Supervised Domain Adaptation for Disparity Estimation with DispNet.
2021	Teaching Assistant: Image Processing
2021	Master Thesis: Julia Guerrero-Viu. Improving Deep Feature Representations for Self-Supervised Training of Disparity Estimation.
2021	Teaching Assistant: Statistical Pattern Recognition
2021 - 2022	Master Thesis: Saurav Shanu. <i>Monocular 3D Object Detection and Bird's Eye View Generation in Driving Scenarios</i> .

2021 - 2022 Master Thesis: Leonhard Sommer. From Pixel Matching to Dynamic Rigid Objects. Master Thesis: Saiprasad Barke. Analysing Multi-view Depth Estimation in a Common Framework. 2023 2023 Master Thesis: Tom Wellinger. Bootstrapping Single-view Depth Estimation via Multi-view Depth Estimation. Master Project: Achim Wimme. Depth-from-video Estimation with a RAFT Model Architecture. 2023 - 2024 2023 - 2024 Teaching Assistant: Computer Vision

#### Education

TU DRESDEN

#### **PhD Student Computer Vision and Deep Learning**

COMPUTER VISION GROUP FREIBURG, HEADED BY PROF. THOMAS BROX

Freiburg i. Br.

10/2012 - 07/2018

since 01/2019

Dresden

Working on 3D reconstruction and 3D generation with a focus on robust application to real-world data.

Information Systems Engineering, Grade: 1.7

• Diplom degree programme (equivalent to M.Sc.).

Student research thesis (equivalent to Bachelor thesis), Chair for Automation Engineering, Grade: 1.0. Title: Developing a SLAM Algorithm for an Omnidirectional Robot Using a ToF Depth Sensor.

Thesis, SICK AG, Waldkirch, Grade: 1.6.

Title: Detection and Mapping of Obstacles for an Automated Guided Vehicle Using a 3D Sensor.

• Degree: Dipl.-Ing. for Information Systems Engineering.

**Electrical Engineering** Dresden TU DRESDEN

Switched to information systems engineering in order to enroll for more computer science courses.

Abitur, Grade: 1.5 Kulmbach MARKGRAF-GEORG-FRIEDRICH-GYMNASIUM 2003 - 2011

# Work Experience

Internship Waldkirch (near Freiburg i. Br.) 5/2017 - 11/2017

SICK AG Gesture recognition using data of a 3D time-of-flight sensor.

Dresden **Research Assistant** 

Chair of Agricultural Systems Technology, TU Dresden
Linux server administration.

• Extending a system for the management of agricultural processes and the analysis of acquired sensor data.

**Research Assistant** Dresden 11/2013 - 9/2014 and 4/2015 - 7/2015

CHAIR OF PROCESS CONTROL SYSTEMS, TU DRESDEN

Development of Android apps building on semantic web technologies.

#### Languages.

German Deutsch ist meine Muttersprache (Native language).

**English** I am highly proficient in spoken and written English (C1).

**French** Je suis bien capable de survivre dans la vie quotidienne (B1 - B2).

Italian Anche parlo un po' di italiano (A1).

# Skills

Programming Python, PyTorch, Numpy, Tensorflow, C++, C, Java, Haskell, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, OpenCV, ROS, Eigen

**Knowledge** Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Robotics (e.g. SLAM, 3D Mapping), 3D sensors, Software engineering

Miscellaneous Linux administration, Git, LTFX, Android app development, SVN

# Activities

Preferably, I spend my free time outdoors and in company of my friends. We often go climbing, as much as possible outdoors, but Sports also indoors in a climbing gym. Apart from climbing, I like running and cycling and go ski touring whenever I have the possibility to go to the Alps.

Travelling All of this works well with my favour for travelling. Doing so, I like to live and move by simple means, for example with bike and tent.

On more quiet days, I also like to stay at home and read a book, or to meet friends and do something together that does not **Friends** necessarily have to involve anything sports-related.